Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.OpenSubtitles.org
We just spotted a pleasure craft
drifting offshore of Haneda.
Recon and intercept.
Over.
Roger that.
We've got the vessel in sight.
From here, there's no apparent
hull damage.
She's called "The Glory Maru."
Requesting owner information now.
In the meantime,
we're going aboard.
We're now on board.
Hello?
Anyone here?
There's no one on the flying deck.
No sign of life.
Just some personal effects.
No traces of an incident.
Maybe a fall overboard?
Vessel's vacant.
We'll prepare a tow.
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
Hey, stop!
Here's all the info
we have so far.
That eruption caused a leak
in the Aqua-Line.
As a result, water is pouring
onto the auto lanes.
A liaison office has already been set up,
and an emergency order issued.
And where's the PM?
He's arriving in 28 minutes.
We'll need intel.
Downstairs.
Right.
First report confirmed at about 8:30 am.
A leak occurred in the
Tokyo Aqua-Line tunnel
near the 2.5 kilo marker.
Seawater entered from a fissure...
Update me as you get info.
Right.
damaged by the flood.
Emergency crews are
currently on the scene.
Hamanami Coast Guard efforts are being
stymied by the steam cloud
that's in the bay.
The Aqua-Line is still closed both ways,
and safety alerts have been
issued throughout the region.
Status report, Mr. Koriyama?
We have a total of
five confirmed collisions
in the tunnel so far.
Was it an earthquake
that caused the flooding?
We're awaiting the seismic readings.
Could it be related to
that strange sea eruption?
We don't know that, not yet at least.
We've got aerials!
An underwater volcanic eruption, maybe?
If so, it's a strange one.
Coast Guard six-nine-one reporting
continued steam eruptions in the bay.
Undersea visibility is currently zero
because of all that churning water.
When the PM arrives, I'm suggesting
a unified initial response.
We'll need to reorganize.
FDMA disaster task force
is currently assembling.
Third Regional Coast Guard HQ
has sealed the bay.
As of now, there is
no sea or air access to the area.
A coastal evacuation advisory
has been issued to the public.
Attention! Please evacuate
the premises immediately!
For your safety, please
follow police instructions
and evacuate to Kisarazu!
What's happening?
Is someone hurt?
This way, and watch your head!
Cool, a slide!
Stay calm.
Heading to first aid.
This place is awesome!
Ow, my feet hurt!
You know, I bet I can sell this footage
to the news.
What was that noise?
C'mon, let's go.
Something's up there.
Please stay calm and seated...
This is bad.
Look, this is starting to freak me out.
Hey, what's that?
What? Wh-Where?
I see it, too.
Sir, the PM's arrived.
We haven't been able
to ascertain the cause
of the tunnel rupture yet.
Never mind the details.
How many fatalities have there been?
- None.
- Then things
aren't as bad as they could be.
Still, there's
a secondary disaster risk.
I've cleared your schedule
so that you can attend
an emergency meeting
in five minutes, sir.
Well then, let's get there.
Obviously, some type of
undersea thermal discharge
has occurred, but do we have
any ideas as to its cause?
The meltdown of an unidentified
nuclear submarine perhaps?
There's no way.
The bay's too shallow
for a sub so that would be impossible.
We believe the fissure was
created by magma steam.
Something that was released
by a new undersea volcano.
Um. Excuse me, sir.
While we did initially believe
that, further study has shown
the epicenter to be
shallow and just steam,
so we're now confident that
it's not volcanic activity.
You should have shared
that info with me sooner!
Sorry, sir.
Another idea forwarded is a new,
large hydrothermal vent.
Yeah, that must be it.
Come on. A vent
directly above the tunnel?
Past geological surveys would
have uncovered it years ago.
Well, maybe it was simply overlooked.
The cause... is something
on the sea floor.
Something, eh? Like what?
A colossal creature, sir.
There's some footage of it online.
That's absurd.
People probably just saw
a big whale spouting.
The sea is boiling.
No living creature could
survive those temperatures.
We've been scouring online
videos, Prime Minister,
but we've yet to find
any conclusive evidence
of the flooding's cause.
Look, time's a wasting here, people.
How about a process of elimination?
I agree. The cause is a new volcano,
or a large thermal vent.
It can't be anything else.
Then we need to plan
our general response,
ladies and gentleman.
Therefore I suggest holding
a cabinet meeting immediately.
Prime Minister?
Yes. Good idea.
In that case, let's move
to the main conference room.
We have to stay
on top of this situation.
Yaguchi.
Listen, you're going
to have to toe the line
on their decision.
Don't stir things up, okay?
I just think that we should
consider every possibility.
You're a rebel. That's good,
but the guy who got you here isn't one.
Got it? Take my advice.
I'm happy to report
that all those injured
in the tunnel are receiving care.
In order to prevent
any further accidents,
fireboats and helicopters have
been mobilized in the bay.
They stand ready to respond. Who's next?
I am. Regarding the
Tokyo Bay coastal region,
we're currently at evacuation
preparedness level one.
Due to possible debris and ash
from the previous incident
and any potential future ones,
we're considering
the possibility of grounding
all flights out of Haneda.
Please forgive me.
I was just handed a correction.
It's been decided to
definitely ground all flights
out of Haneda to ensure citizen safety.
No flights will be going in
or out until further notice.
In regards to
the undersea volcano-induced
flooding of the Aqua-Line Tunnel,
it's fortunate that
no toxic gases whatsoever
have been detected thus far.
A team from the Meteorological
Agency has been mobilized.
As has a group of experts
from the Coast Guard.
And both are now currently
on route to conduct
a thorough investigation of the cause.
Everyone. I've been notified
that eruption activity
is dying down rapidly!
Huh?
Is it over?
No big deal, I guess.
Sir. With all due respect,
I must reiterate the presence
of a large marine creature...
as a possible cause.
Yaguchi, this is a serious
matter. Not some joke.
I agree. This is a ministerial
meeting after all.
Don't make a mockery of it.
And with no time frame for restoration,
we can expect...
Sir? There's been another incident.
Turn on the TV.
Sorry! But we have
to suspend this meeting!
The TV! Turn it on now!
It's unbelievable! Look at
the size of it! I...
and I doubt anyone else...
has ever seen anything like it before!
A few minutes ago, this strange...
Wh-What is that thing?
- A tail?
- It appears so.
I guess Yaguchi's "joke"
is no laughing matter after all, huh?
This meeting's adjourned!
All cabinet heads, please,
let's assemble in the Prime
Minister's office right away!
Eyewitness News chopper just...
So what is this thing?
"Giant Unidentified Lifeform," sir.
That's what we're calling it
for now. But, um...
That name, it will
more than likely change
since we're currently
compiling a list of
leading biologists and
scientists to consult with
on the subject. Once done,
they'll come here
for an emergency meeting
to ascertain what this
thing is and what we should call it.
We need to know now!
Get them here!
- Right!
- Sir.
Until these folks arrive,
we should focus on
something else. Our response.
Yes, of course.
How do we respond to
something that's unprecedented?
I think that the choices are
obviously quite simple.
We can do nothing and just let it go,
or capture it, try to exterminate it,
or possibly even
attempt to chase it off.
I vote for extermination.
And I concur. Look at
the costs incurred already
with the tunnel, and the
Haneda flight groundings.
Plus, if Tokyo Bay remains
closed indefinitely,
those costs are going
to skyrocket, gentlemen.
I agree, and vote to exterminate it.
Me, too. The sooner, the better.
And you? Defense?
Eeh...
While it's true that we have prepared
for a wildlife-based threat
before, it was never with
self-defense forces
using weapons in the bay.
I vote no.
Well, in that case, why blow it up?
Can't we chase it off?
If I may.
We might want to factor in the
public's opinion, as well.
So, you know, academics
and environmentalists
are raising a stink
and they're calling for
its live capture as a new species.
No, let's kill it.
A few torpedoes won't hurt the bay.
The use of weapons actually could,
and that's why I'm advocating
for a live capture instead.
I do as well.
I think capturing the thing
is our best option at this point.
Go gather all the intel
you can on the lifeform.
And the options for
extermination, capture,
and expulsion and what
those things might require.
Seems like they're evenly
divided, aren't they?
Sorry, who are you addressing?
A vapor cloud's been spotted moving
near the Tama River!
What? "Moving"?
It's alive, isn't it?
The creature's just off of
Haneda Airport, near Runway D,
and it appears to be
entering the Tama River.
Whoa!
We just got a report from
the Bayshore Expressway!
It's flooding!
Damn, not again!
Forget capturing it.
Sir. Three experts have arrived.
I suggest we go consult
with them right now.
From the TV images, it's indiscernible
whether this thing could
possibly be a relic dinosaur
or some undiscovered whale species.
In my opinion,
the creature is a heretofore
unknown aquatic species.
But I can't say for certain
without an examination.
Since I don't know if
this footage is legitimate,
I cannot say. If I comment
on unverified evidence...
I could lose my
credibility as a biologist.
It's wrapping up.
We'll resume shortly.
Can't be good if it's already over.
Sorry to say, but that was
a huge waste of time.
I agree, sir.
Those experts were useless.
Get me some people who know something.
On it, sir.
Shimura. Any ideas?
Well, I do have a college friend
who's with the Environment
Ministry, but she's low-ranking.
That's okay, call her now.
This creature...
it appears to be serpentine
with auxiliary ambulation, and
even though it possesses gills,
it also has legs
just like a lungfish does.
Huh. If it has legs
then can it come on land?
Yes, it's a possibility.
If it does, who stops it?
Well, frankly, we haven't
determined which agency
it falls under yet, sir.
Um, one of our scientists
is of the belief
that the creature's fin-like
feet would more than likely
be crushed by the immense
weight of its own body.
So it coming ashore should be
physiologically impossible.
We can't be sure of that since we're
dealing with an unknown animal.
Is that so? Do you
share this view as well?
I apologize for the deputy
chief's lack of decorum, sir,
but just as your experts
have already concluded,
I believe the creature coming
on land is quite improbable.
I see.
Sir. Regarding the
damage to the tunnels...
I'd like to humbly suggest
that the sooner we hold
an official press conference to
calm the public, the better.
But sir, I must stress this,
please be careful that you
only give out information
that's been verified thus far.
Let's do this.
Please get my uniform ready.
Earlier in the day,
both the Aqua-Line
and Tama River tunnels
sustained significant damage.
We're currently tracking
the creature responsible
as it moves up the Nomi River.
We've yet to positively
identify what sort of
animal it is, but we don't believe
that it can come on land.
Even though it's unlikely,
should it beach itself
in the bay's shallows
there is no need to fear.
Our experts believe its own
weight would crush it to death.
I repeat, there is no danger
of the creature coming ashore.
So please set your minds at ease.
Thank you. That will be all.
Sir, sorry to interrupt.
What? It has?
Well, well. No danger
of coming ashore, huh?
Well, now what? I was
just proven a liar on TV!
But sir, like Akasaka said,
you were only supposed
to give verified info!
I wanted to reassure the public.
How's that thing ashore?
We don't know.
We've posed that question
to our experts and
are waiting to hear back.
To hell with them.
We have to act.
Sir. We need to set up emergency
disaster control headquarters now.
Then do it.
This cabinet council
meeting is now adjourned.
Let's get to work.
There's so much bureaucracy involved.
Every action requires a meeting.
Come on, don't knock red tape.
It's the foundation of democracy.
Why does there have to be so much
for a press conference?
In the last few hours, we have set up
emergency disaster control headquarters.
Its sole purpose is to combat
the Giant Unidentified Lifeform
that has come ashore.
We are crafting a full-scale response
to secure citizen safety,
and that includes
coordinated evacuation with both Tokyo
and federal government agencies.
Evacuation instructions
will be issued shortly
for areas along the creature's path.
The creature is currently headed
towards Shinagawa.
We're clocking it at a speed of
about 13 kilometers an hour.
For something so big,
it moves quite slowly.
But it could still
reach Tokyo in three hours
- at that pace.
- Just imagine what
that thing could do to this city.
Good God. The damage here
would be catastrophic.
Let's exterminate this thing right now!
Not in densely-populated areas!
We have to evacuate the citizens first.
Have MIC and MLIT set up
evacuation zones and transport.
The PM's ordered us to conduct
evacuation measures!
Report to your stations!
I thought the orders
would have come much sooner.
I can't say I'm surprised.
The First Reponses manual
doesn't cover this.
An evacuation due to a monster.
What's more, an expedited one.
We've never even drilled for this type
of action before, sir.
Plus, a city-wide evacuation
will more than likely
cause a general panic.
There'll be mass gridlock with everyone
trying to leave the city.
In that case, we'll make every effort
to control the traffic.
Traffic signals are out of order.
For your safety,
please leave your vehicles
and follow police and safety
personnel instructions.
Attention! Attention!
A full evacuation of
Shinagawa has been issued.
All residents are required to evacuate
the area immediately.
Hon! Hurry!
At this rate the city'll be in ruins.
Contact Public Safety.
Get them on the horn now.
Tell them we're requesting
Self-Defense Forces
to come exterminate that thing.
So they want to use weapons?
Correct. Article 76
says in an armed attack,
Self-Defense troops
are allowed to use force.
But this doesn't
qualify as an armed attack.
And to be accurate,
Article 76 stipulates
"by an aggressor country
or equivalent force."
Not some monster.
We don't have time
to argue over semantics.
Only the SDF is equipped to respond.
This request, it means soldiers
engaging in urban combat.
That's certainly going to give
the Prime Minister pause.
All due respect,
but we need a response with
a two-pronged approach.
Military force and citizen evacuation.
I also urge you to declare
a state of emergency.
Right now, it appears
that we have only one option,
and that's mobilization
for defense, of course.
But we can only do that
on your orders, sir.
You're talking about a
declaration with no precedent.
We'd be... mobilizing
the country for war.
What's more, the police are still
evacuating thousands of people.
If we launch a military strike,
there is a high likelihood
of collateral damage
in terms of casualties.
I don't want that.
The US forces that are here.
Can't we get them to kill this
beast under the Security Treaty?
No, our government and SDF,
we have to move first here.
Even under the Treaty, the US
can only provide support.
We're facing a living organism.
And an unknown one, so aggravating it
might lead to more damage.
It is an organism.
And that means, we can stop
the thing in its tracks.
And unlike an earthquake or a typhoon,
we can halt its progress.
Lives, sir. That should
be our top priority.
Sir, I know this must
be a difficult decision,
but to prevent further calamity
your authorization is needed now.
Wait, right this instant?
You're serious?
Time is wasting. Your answer.
Moments ago, the Prime Minister declared
a national state
of emergency in response
to the giant creature
that has come ashore.
He's also called for
the first-ever mobilization
of Self-Defense Forces
in this nation's history.
This makes it Japan's
first military action
since World War II, and when
asked for justification,
the Prime Minister referenced
the terminology in Article 76.
Nerima 1st Division was dispatched
at Tokyo's request.
While this group has been tasked with
guiding both rescue
and evacuation efforts,
I must stress that they are
not equipped for battle.
I'd say attack helicopters
would be our best defense.
- Contact Kisarazu Base.
- Sir!
Shall we deploy F-2s from Misawa Base?
No. Any civilian
casualties could destroy
the SDF forever.
So let's minimize firepower.
But we still don't know
this thing's strength.
I think we need to be prepared
for anything in this case.
I agree. That's why
I'm going to recommend
an integrated, three-force operation.
Call the PM.
According to this plan, the joint force
will be led by the Eastern Army.
The goal is extermination.
The ground troops.
They'll continue to evacuate
all of the citizens.
With your permission,
our rapid response helicopters
will attack the creature.
Sir, it's very likely that some elderly
and infirm people might
still remain in the city.
That's why I can't make a decision
without an inspection first.
Unfortunately, under
conditions like these,
I'd say some collateral damage
is unavoidable now.
Sir, I know this isn't easy for you,
but we need a decision.
Understood.
This is a risky mission against
an unknown enemy.
Did this group volunteer?
No, standard rotation.
They said this is what
they signed up for, sir.
Pilots! Good luck!
Lifting off from Kisarazu at 13:08.
ETA 13:20, over.
What a relief this is.
That thing will be dead soon.
I'm sure the choppers
will make short work of it.
Yeah. I bet we could turn its carcass
into a big tourist attraction.
Sirs. Just as a reminder,
the Old Imperial Army thought like that.
During the last war,
their armchair theories
led to the loss of three
million Japanese lives.
So beware of unfounded optimism.
Please watch your step!
Remain calm!
This way, please!
Pick up the pace!
Local evacuation centers are useless!
Tell us where to send
these people! Hurry!
The creature's progression!
Somehow it's suddenly stopped!
Stopped? But why now?
Look.
It's evolving.
Attacker 1, this is CP, over.
Copy that, CP, over.
Head to holding area 2
to await further orders. Over.
Attacker 1. Copy.
It's not like we were told.
CP, it's Attacker 1.
Target differs from report, and
that thing is much bigger now.
Attacker 1.
Hold your position
and await further instructions. Over.
I was just informed that resident
evacuation is complete.
Excellent. Minister,
we're now ready to open fire.
Understood.
Well, sir, we'll fire at your command.
Say the word.
Very well. Fire.
Attacker 1, you have
a greenlight from the PM.
Commence fire on the creature.
I repeat, commence fire. Over.
Copy that, CP.
Commencing fire.
Target in sight.
Aim straight for the head.
Ready. Aim.
Wait, hold your fire!
Why aren't they firing?
We just spotted a few civilians
near the line of fire!
Civies present. Can we fire?
Can we fire if civilians are present?
So do we wait?
Or do we fire?
Civilians present.
So do we proceed or abort?
Sir. Your answer. We need it!
Now, sir!
Abort. Call it off.
Do it now.
We must protect civilians!
Attacker 1, abort and move
to holding positions. Over.
Copy that CP. Over.
The creature is currently
on the move again.
It's breaking through the expressway
and appears to be headed
towards Tokyo Bay.
All flights out of Narita
have been canceled.
We have several reports of fires
blazing out of control...
The Transit Authority verified that...
Meanwhile, pledges of support
continue to pour in from...
and more supplies and aid workers
are said to be on their way here now.
The Tokyo Stock Exchange will be
open as usual today.
Barring any unforeseen events,
the bullet-train is
operating shuttle service
from Shin-Yokohama.
Scientific envoys from France
and other nations
have arrived in an attempt
to help the government
ascertain the exact nature...
so the search zone is
being expanded to cover a
much wider area. Officials...
bringing the total number
of confirmed casualties
to 100 at this hour,
but rescue personnel are still...
reportedly been put out.
While government officials
search for the creature,
Disaster Management Minister Kanai
is leading an envoy to survey and assess
the damage that it's caused.
It was ashore for what, maybe two hours?
And it did all this?
No. We did wasting time
with our response.
It's our fault.
We didn't know what it
could do. It surprised us.
Everyone did their best
in the circumstances.
So don't be so damn smug.
It's time to speak to the press,
Minister Kanai.
This way, please.
Okay.
We've arrived at the coordinates
that you requested, Captain.
Full stop, begin scanning operation.
We believe the creature more than likely
submerged itself somewhere
on the seafloor off Kanaya.
So then, we've stepped up patrols
and strengthened our
surveillance around Chiba
and Sagami Bay as well.
But if that thing's hiding
somewhere in the Sagami Trough,
detection's a moot point.
Who knows when or where than damn thing
will emerge next?
How are the preparations coming along?
A rapid land strategy at
water's edge won't be easy.
I suggest multiple plans.
I agree, so get to work devising them.
I want to see numerous ones
for a landing point
encounter and expeditionary pursuit.
- Right.
- Sir. I'll get on them.
And they will include a number
of different artillery,
tank, and F-2 scenarios.
Well, well.
Defensive operations
lean heavily on Kanto.
I knew the metro area
would take top priority.
Yep. Sounds like a fifth floor order.
But why Kanto and not the other regions?
Well, you see, in regards
to the other regions...
at least in terms of the GNP...
they make up 17% of the total.
But Kanto, on the
other hand, it makes up
a whopping 40% of it.
Gotta admit that sounds like
a real prudent strategy to me.
I'd hate to make that decision.
That's right, and in fact,
they've even set up
a special response team
in the PM residence.
You don't say.
I also heard you were
appointed its bureau chief.
Well, look at you.
You're big time.
But I still need you to pick the team.
Can you do that for me?
'Course I can.
I'll bring you people who'll
speak their minds to the PM.
Good. I'll need them.
- I'm Tachikawa.
- I'm Takeo.
Ready, lift.
My name's Rando Yaguchi.
Thank you all for coming here.
This operation'll be an informal one.
Titles and seniority
don't mean anything here
and you can speak freely.
Well, that's it.
I'm nominally in charge,
and we're relying on you,
a crack team of lone wolves,
nerds, troublemakers,
academic heretics, freaks, and general
pains-in-the-butt-of-the-bureaucracy.
We need your expertise.
So let's have it.
Here are the basic specs
we have on the creature,
so find out what you can.
- Is this all?
- Yeah, that's all.
We have to fill in
the blanks for the rest.
If you have any info
whatsoever, share it.
Yes, since yesterday's
so-called "experts,"
they were too baffled
to conclude anything,
and then people died as a result.
This is a simple profile I put together.
It shows the three mutations
we've seen so far.
I believe that more are coming.
What is this thing?
Um, well. We're analyzing a sample of
its body fluid at our lab to find out.
If you pass some samples onto me,
I can get us outside help.
Yeah, I'd love to do that,
but the US took everything we had left.
As for the on-site remains,
they're currently being burned
because of the stench.
Yeah, I heard.
And at the insistence of the Americans.
Then we leave the analysis to you.
Okay, what about its behavioral biology?
Well, behaviorally, all that
it's done so far is move,
so we can't determine intellect.
Based on that fact, I think that
communication with it is unlikely.
One simple question.
What's this thing's energy source?
It's big. So huge that
it would need an enormous
amount of energy not just to move,
but also metabolically.
But at that size,
oxygen conversion in its
digestive tract just wouldn't be enough.
Maybe the answer...
is nuclear fission?
Sense of humor, Miss Ogashira?
That's impossible.
A US carrier is leaving port?
Correct. We heard that Yokosuka City's
radiation monitoring alert went
off and that could be why.
Let me check.
I'll call the Nuclear
Regulation Authority.
I have orders not to
go public about this just yet,
but radiation levels in the metro area
have risen in the last day.
Could this be caused
by a leak somewhere?
Have you checked?
Yes. My team's inspected
all of the nation's reactors
and didn't find a leak at any of them.
Then where's it coming from?
Is this even possible?
What?
Quick! Here, look at this!
This data shows
radiation spikes that match
the path the creature took.
Look at this!
See?
Miss Ogashira was right after all.
Sorry.
This information has
apparently already gone viral.
That isn't good. Contact the
Chief Cabinet Secretary.
This will be trouble.
The PM needs to call a press
conference right away, sir.
Actually, I think we should hold off.
Unless you can absolutely prove
that the creature's radioactive,
this could set off a huge wave of panic.
And it's not enough of a spike
to warrant evacuation.
We also don't have any legal
grounds to implement one.
But still, we are dealing
with elevated radiation.
Please remember that.
You're right. We can't wait.
I'll talk to the PM.
You there.
Schedule a briefing with
the PM in five minutes.
Yes. President Ross.
I understand. Thank you.
So many unilateral requests.
Typically, American.
I've got word about
an assistant Deputy Chief
to the US President.
They're requesting a secret
meeting with the PM.
They move fast, don't they?
Yeah. He just left Yokota Air Base
and is already en route to see the PM.
The Foreign Ministry's
in an uproar, of course.
Oh, and this Deputy Chief's aide.
They made a request and are
coming here to meet with you.
With me? But why?
I need someone within the government
that I can work with.
I'm familiar with your record
and your interesting history,
so the most obvious choice is you.
Don't you think?
Well. I'm honored, but Hideki Akasaka
would be a better choice.
Thanks, but he turned me down already.
All I need is a favor
that won't stain my record.
I want you to find someone for me.
And who might that be?
A man who foresaw
the coming of that creature
many years before
it ravaged your country.
Are you interested?
We know he landed
at Narita seven days ago.
Goro Maki.
Japanese. Former professor.
I hear that your
intelligence agency is...
First-rate.
And what's in it for us?
Give us Goro Maki and we'll give you
all the intel we have on your creature.
But listen. Let's keep this
op bilateral, okay?
Just US-Japan. So, win-win.
Understood. Let's get to it.
Thank you.
Ugh! I rushed to Yokota
straight from a party
so I didn't have time to change.
Where's a Zara?
Kayoco Anne Patterson.
She's very young.
America admirably values
performance over age,
and she's Senator Patterson's daughter.
Ah, the same one
behind the Kern Agreement.
Formidable. A mixture of
talent, pedigree,
and coattail-riding, huh?
I suspect she's not really your type.
Nope. Since she uses
her father's connections
in such an unabashed way,
she's the political type.
Like Yaguchi.
A search at a time like this?
It's for Rando Yaguchi.
I owe his father a debt, a great one.
Use as many agents as you need.
This is the subject's profile.
A professor who was
expelled from his university
and left Japan as a result.
Although a biologist,
he ended up working for
an energy firm in
the US. Interesting guy.
Is this a red notice?
No. You just need to locate him.
Once he's found, the NSA
or CIA, they'll move in.
And discreetly, I hear.
His last known whereabouts.
My grandmother's homeland
certainly works fast.
Goro Maki's missing.
His boat was found
adrift a few days ago,
but there was no trace of him.
Miss Patterson.
Were you only looking for Goro Maki?
- Or this as well?
- Yeah, that too.
"Now do as you please.
I did the same."
His last words?
Do you want to confirm this?
No need.
I trust you. This is in special ink,
it can't be copied.
I'll just take photos then,
to share with my team.
God... zilla?
That's right.
It's the DOE's code name.
Godzilla. He gave it an English name.
Gojira. What's it mean?
I found one link.
On Ohdo island where Maki's from,
Gojira means "god incarnate."
A violent one.
That's apparently why he put
"God" in the name he gave it.
In Japanese,
the characters read "Gojira."
"Gojira..." you say?
Who cares about its name at this point?
It sounds ridiculous.
It's just as well,
the name originated in the US.
At least now we know what
to call it. "Gojira."
Just in, and according
to multiple sources,
in regards to the giant creature,
"Gojira" is the unofficial name by which
the government is calling it.
Goro Maki?
An ex-biology professor
at Jonan U, huh?
Find out all that
you can about this guy.
Do so and you'll get an exclusive
when the time's right to go to print.
That's a promise.
Hope that's enticing enough.
Yep. It sure is.
Sixty years ago.
So this is all about unregulated dumping
of radioactive materials.
Don't tell me.
Gojira fed on these.
Yes. That's the DOE's conclusion.
They sent requests
to various institutions
to analyze what exactly had
been held in those containers.
Goro Maki was on staff
at one who responded.
According to him, this thing wasn't just
an ancient species of marine life.
But now, one also surrounded
by radioactive waste.
Exposure didn't kill this creature,
but mutated it into
an entirely new lifeform.
And that is his Godzilla theory.
But it's continuing
to mutate since its body
lengthened and changed
after it came ashore.
Yes. It can somehow
mutate itself to live
on both land and sea.
I have to admit
its capabilities far surpass
anything I could ever imagine.
This is all the
information at my disposal.
What comes next?
Personal service.
Oh.
This is what Goro Maki left behind?
Mhmmm.
I can't make sense of it.
This thing's not a molecular array,
so how's it relate to Gojira?
Well, perhaps it's an analytical table.
One with structural layers.
Even though Maki intentionally left out
some final data in
his original hypothesis,
we now have the complete
version we can study.
We'd like to analyze
that info. Can we do that?
Sure.
I'm bad at Japanese honorifics,
so can we be informal?
In that case,
can you tell me what it is
that the US wants with
Gojira? Capture or kill?
That's for the president to decide.
Who is it that decides in your country?
So, the cabinet finally made a decision
on the relief and recovery bill?
If you thought that was
an interagency nightmare,
wait until the Gojira bill.
- Yeah.
- I guarantee a lack of
precedent's going to
cloud orders, and I bet
you can expect a lot of passing
the buck to happen, too.
I can't believe it.
The security bill passed so easily.
Foreign Ministry muscle,
and US pressure, of course.
From what I've
been told about that deal,
the US wants to use its Gojira
info as a diplomatic card.
Well, if that's the case
let's pray that Aide Akasaka
can handle the White House.
Based on all the analysis we've done,
I can positively say
that these gamma rays
match no known elements whatsoever.
It's unprecedented.
Gojira is it?
Its body is harboring new elements
that are unknown to science.
Well, this certainly explains why
the US Department of Energy
moved so quickly.
Take this data with us.
Call the PM.
Right.
Understood. This is going
to complicate things.
So... how much do we say?
Having fully analyzed
substances recovered
from its path, we can
confirm the following...
In the stricken area,
radiation has risen
to point-five sieverts but is not...
Thanks for the food.
Yes, thank you.
Even with this new
information the US agreed
to share with us, I still think
we can expect some gridlock.
Yeah, Riken's report had impact,
but in addition to that,
Gojira has eight times
the amount of genetic info of humans.
It's literally gonna
take us years to sequence
all of that genetic material.
I think we can agree Gojira is the most
evolved creature
this planet has ever seen.
Capable of self-mutation
to best fit the
environment that it's in.
That trumps human intelligence.
It's still mortal, though.
So it can be killed.
I sure hope so.
That's exactly what we're
all here to find out, Professor.
Well, does anyone have
any clues into its behavior?
All it does is walk.
One thing I don't understand.
Why did it return to Tokyo Bay?
That's it.
For cooling.
Gojira has something
akin to a nuclear reactor
in its body, and its fins
must serve as heat vents.
And if that is indeed
the case, then its blood
more than likely serves as
the body's cooling system!
I get it. You're saying that
it temporarily retrogressed
to sea creature so it could
adjust its body temperature
after mutating, eh?
Maybe our only hope
is to try and find a way
to shut it down.
Its internal cooling system, that is.
Then not only would we
need to force Gojira
to shut off its internal
reactor to stay alive,
but also find a way
to cool its blood down,
and so much so that we can
immobilize the creature.
Just as a suggestion,
what about administering
a blood-coagulating drug?
Wait, is that even possible
with Gojira upright?
We'll investigate
a few practical methods.
Perhaps a compression
pump system like this.
We, the Health Ministry
and METI, will gather all of
the necessary coagulant and equipment
that will be required for this op.
We're submitting this to the Prime Minister
as "The Yaguchi Plan."
Understood.
Name aside.
Let's get to it.
Sir.
Gojira's God, save Gojira!
Care for some tea, sir?
Yes. Thanks so much.
Thank you, ma'am.
Hey. We need a break.
- Okay.
- All right.
Got it.
I see everyone voluntarily
doing whatever they can.
They haven't gone home
to rest even though
they've all been urged to.
There are some staff members
who've actually brought in
hot meals for everybody that's here.
It's very inspiring.
No jurisdictional infighting.
No arguments between ministries.
Just people working together
for the common good.
And not just staff, either.
There're a lot of outsiders who've
volunteered their time, too.
Yeah, you're right.
There's hope for this country.
That there is.
Just one question, though.
When was the last time
you changed that shirt?
Mm?
To be honest, your shirt
smells pretty rank.
Really?
A shower and a change
of clothes wouldn't hurt.
Yaguchi! Gojira's
resurfaced in Sagami Bay!
And it's coming ashore!
J-Alert!
The lifeform designated
"Gojira" has come ashore!
Primary evacuation order over
Em-net has been transmitted!
This is an emergency evacuation order.
This is not a drill.
A colossal-sized, unidentified creature
has come ashore.
For public safety, citizens are urged
to evacuate the city immediately.
Repeat, evacuate immediately.
Please follow the instructions
of police and fire personnel.
The Prime Minster.
On its current route,
Gojira's moving towards Kamariya.
Wait. Am I crazy
or has it gotten bigger?
Yes, and beyond expectation.
Both its face and body look different!
Yes. Its size has nearly doubled.
Gojira's evolved
and into its fourth form.
Oh no, this is going to be disastrous.
Attention! Citizens are to take refuge
indoors immediately!
This area is now under official curfew
and the streets must be cleared!
Attention!
You are in a designated
evacuation zone and
must leave the area now!
Please proceed and follow the directions
of police and safety personnel!
Gojira is currently projected
to reach Tokyo in three hours.
But why the hell is it coming here?
An armed assault on
its body has potential risks.
Namely the release
of radioactive materials
into the surrounding region.
So, preventing it from
reaching the metro area,
that must be our top
priority, in my opinion.
I hear this thing lives
on radioactive material.
If this Gojira were to
attack a nuclear facility,
this disaster would be far worse.
Sir. We must stop it, and stop it now.
That's right. And also
because if we don't,
we'll be viewed overseas as timid.
How is your Yaguchi Plan coming along?
Regrettably, it's not ready yet.
All you have to do is give the order
and the SDF will do its job.
The state of emergency
is still in effect,
so the only one
who can order an attack...
is you, and you alone.
Well, sir?
I know.
Commence attack.
Right away, sir.
Contact command.
Right.
The Prime Minister
has just ordered an attack.
We've been given
unrestricted weapon use.
With this directive, we must
do whatever it takes
to prevent Gojira from reaching Tokyo.
So Plan B if it goes to Kanagawa?
Yes. We'll make Kawasaki
the primary battleground.
Are we clear on that?
Yes, sir. And the Tama River will be our
absolute defense line.
Let's go kill that thing.
Taxi to holding point B1.
Runway one-zero.
Runway one-zero
cleared for takeoff.
Attack formation report
five miles west. P0304 now
embarking from Tachikawa.
Tanks and artillery have been deployed
to Maruko Bridge.
Roger. Ready attack positions.
Please let this work.
Eight minutes to contact with target!
We're really engaging in live fire?
Just relax.
It's like our drills.
The target's body contains
radioactive material.
So pinpoint your attacks solely
on the thing's head and legs.
All battalions ready to fire.
Target approaching!
ETA is three minutes and counting!
First to fourth chopper squadrons
are arriving now!
CO1, this is CP, over.
Copy CP. CO1, over.
CO1 to PP1.
PO1 in flight over
Musahi-Kosugi, holding at BP1.
PO2 to PO4 behind towers.
Standby at Holding Area 2, over.
CO1 ready to engage at PP1.
Target distance at 1,200 meters.
Roger. Maintain positions, over.
All helicopter reconnaissance
has now been completed.
Total area evacuation
has been confirmed.
Koriyama.
Are you sure this time?
No stragglers?
I trust the report that
we received from the field.
Madame. The target is advancing.
Sir, please authorize the use of force.
I authorize its use.
Commence.
The PM just confirmed the order.
Commence fire.
Light that thing up.
Phase 1 is now a go, Commander.
Commence fire.
Repeat, commence fire. Over.
CO1 copy. Commencing fire.
Ready. Fire!
Autocannon direct hits
are thus far ineffective!
Try the Apache's 30 millimeter.
Let's give it a shot.
Third squadron in reconnaissance.
Report on effectiveness, over.
Third squadron on site. Target is fine.
No effect.
So 16,000 rounds of machine gun fire
and it didn't leave a scratch.
Get HQ and the PM.
It's the Commander.
He's requesting to use missiles.
It's a dense area,
but we have no other choice.
Permission to use missiles, sir?
I authorize... the use of all weapons.
Give the word!
CO1, switch weapons systems to missiles.
When you've got a lock on the
target, fire them all, over!
Roger! PO1 to PO4, switch to missiles.
Target straight ahead 700 meters!
Locked on!
Ready. Fire!
Keep giving that thing hell, boys!
All direct hits, but no
visible damage sustained,
and it's still alive.
Even missiles don't work?
What is this thing?
Nothing's piercing
the skin of that monster!
Time to shift to Phase ♪2.
Copy that, Commander.
Commencing to Phase 2 of the operation.
Commence fire.
Repeat, commence fire.
Roger that. This is Tiger 1.
Commencing fire.
Type 10 tanks, aim for the target's legs
and unleash a concentrated barrage
on the commander's order!
Ready. Lock on.
There it is!
Distance good!
Fire!
Direct hit! Keep firing!
The target, it's decreased speed!
Good! It's working!
Now commence artillery fire!
Time to target.
Seven... six... five... four...
three... two... one...
Impact!
All hit target! Fusillade. Fire!
Sir, the target has just been sighted
entering the Tama River!
Tell Gotemba to attack.
Launch all rockets!
The target! It's halted!
Time to move to Phase 3.
Launch the aerial assault on Gojira.
Type 10 tanks, shift to Phase 3!
I repeat, all tanks shift to
Phase 3 positions immediately!
Roger. Cleared for attack.
Ready. Aim. Now!
Bombs away!
Laser on. Tracking.
Bullseye!
The target is turning northwest!
Repeat, it's heading northwest!
It's turning away?
You mean this plan is working?
JDAM second wave's next.
Yes, that'll finish it off.
Way to go!
All tanks retreat now!
Evacuate! Get the hell out of here now!
- Mayday!
- Come on. Come on.
Attention, target
has crossed into Tokyo!
ACP, CO1. Choppers are out of munitions!
Repeat, munitions exhausted!
Tiger 1, this is 40.
Give us a status report over.
This is Tiger 1.
Eight squads are out of ammo.
Three tanks are severely damaged,
and two others are crippled, over.
It's confirmed, sirs.
The forward command post
has been destroyed!
The target's breached the defense line!
Our defensive position
has collapsed entirely!
Sir, that creature.
It's still within artillery range.
Let's continue the assault.
We can't. Those wards still
aren't fully evacuated yet.
Sorry, but I'm afraid
that's all we can do.
Understood.
We'll suspend the operation.
We couldn't stop it.
Sorry, sir.
Don't lose hope.
It's our job to protect the people here.
An offensive isn't the only way.
Speed up the evacuation.
The operation failed, and Gojira
is once again on the move.
The SDF's full power
was futile against it.
That thing's self-preservation
ability is amazing.
Standard weapons won't take it down,
that's why we're here, remember?
An organism that surpasses
man in every way.
The target's been sighted
entering Meguro Ward!
Sir! Let's petition
the US for military aid
in taking it down.
It's our only choice!
Sir. I just heard from the USAF.
They've confirmed that a squadron
of stealth bombers is already en route.
Submit a formal cooperation request
to the US. I'm on my way
to meet with the ambassador.
With your authorization,
I'll hold a press
conference on the subject.
And so, we've requested aid by US forces in fighting
Gojira based on the Japan-US Security which...
The proposed US bombing zone.
It's this large?
The damage will be worse than Gojira!
The bombing zone's so vast.
We'll have to evacuate
everyone underground!
The US will soon launch an attack
on Gojira! Please evacuate
to the nearest subway
or underground shelter at this time!
Stop pushing!
This residence is directly
in Gojira's path, sir.
And since the SDF failed
to stop this thing,
the US military might fail, too.
You're saying...
that we should evacuate?
Yes! Both you and the entire cabinet!
For the nation to function,
you need to leave
for the secondary facility
in Tachikawa quickly!
Just as the US strike is about to begin?
No, I have a duty to stay
and monitor its execution!
And besides that, I can't
abandon the citizens here!
You must leave.
Remember, you have an
entire nation to protect
but you can't do that
if you're dead, sir.
So please evacuate.
Tokyo City Hall is still functioning.
So for right now, please,
let the governor take charge.
Very well.
Sir, two choppers'll be on the roof.
My group will travel there by car.
Okay. Get going.
I'm sure it'll take some time.
Traffic is going to be murder.
We'll see you there.
Right. We'll get moving.
Attention!
A mandatory evacuation
order has been issued!
Hurry everyone!
Please vacate the premises at once!
Repeat, a mandatory evacuation
order has been issued!
Please vacate the premises at once!
It's gridlock all over
the city. Traffic isn't moving.
Even so, the strike's still coming.
We need to get everyone out.
So that's Gojira.
Just got word.
The strike's going to occur
ahead of schedule!
MOP II bombs have struck the target.
Direct hit!
It's confirmed bleeding!
This may work!
Nice job USA.
Sir. The helicopters are arriving.
Quickly everyone! Down this way!
What's that glow?
Gojira's back has begun
to glow all of a sudden, sir!
No more details than that!
What can it be glowing for?
That's everyone!
Come on, Yaguchi!
There's an emergency call
from Yokota Air Base.
B-2, Number 1 seems to have been downed!
But there's no way.
That's impossible!
Godzilla.
Truly a god incarnate.
The target is shooting some
unidentified weapon from the front.
Bomber 2 and Bomber 3
will circle in from behind.
Payback time.
Roger. Payback.
The Prime Minister and his cabinet
are on board and
en route to Tachikawa...
High levels of radiation
have been projected.
For their safety,
people are urged to
remain indoors for at least
another 49 hours.
How much radiation the creature
has released on Tokyo is still unknown.
Due to the attack, expect emergency
services to be severely delayed.
I hear radioactivity is high.
Will the government
distribute iodine tablets?
Authorities are urging residents...
Nuclear, biological, and chemical
response teams are being
deployed throughout the city
for decontamination and rescue.
A government spokesperson
stated that these teams
will arrive in all affected areas...
The Prime Minister, Cabinet Secretary,
and five ministers are still
missing at this hour,
and presumed dead after their helicopter
was blown from the sky.
Police headquarters and two ministries
still remain intact.
Other government buildings
didn't fare as well...
to describe what I'm
looking at right now is "apocalyptic."
It's almost like looking
at the historic photos
of Hiroshima and Nagasaki
after the bombs were dropped,
but then you realize
what you're staring at
is actually right in front of you.
refugees left homeless
in the city are estimated
to be in the millions,
and that number is rising every hour.
With the Prime Minister presumed dead,
government officials are racing
to select an acting PM
to fill the political vacuum created by
the tragic events of last night.
With the PM residence still
in the path of danger,
government headquarters
are being moved to Tachikawa City.
Several miles from the city
center, it's hoped it will be
a safer location for the
government's base of operations.
Attention, all staff.
Decontamination protocols
have been enacted.
Interior access...
Chief Yaguchi!
- I'll call you back.
- Izumi, you're safe.
Yeah, only for one reason.
It's because I went home
on Friday night.
That's the sole thing that saved me.
Hey. Do you know that you're bleeding?
- You okay?
- Yeah, sorry.
They said bandages were in short supply.
I know, everything is.
Tokyo is directing fire and rescue.
We have no Internal Ministry yet.
Let the police handle refugees.
We're working on it, okay?
They'll have to hold out
for one more night.
Rumors will fly,
so get on the press now.
I need information now.
Where's Gojira?
It's inactive near Tokyo Station.
And the reason for that?
Who knows why?
And radiation levels?
The Nuclear Regulation Authority.
They're out getting readings right now.
They did inform me earlier
that radiation is dripping
from Gojira's mouth,
but it's only trace amounts.
Gojira's radioactive plume
blew out to sea,
but contamination is still widespread.
So then the hardest-hit areas
aren't just uninhabitable now.
They're contaminated as well.
Yeah, conditions are
about as dire as they can get.
We're lacking in manpower, materials,
and even political infrastructure.
They're all dead.
The Prime Minister and
the Chief Cabinet Secretary.
Everyone who was on the evac chopper.
Don't go to pieces!
We'll just make do with
the few staff that's left!
Yaguchi.
Calm down first, okay?
I'm sorry.
Who's been made the acting PM?
The ruling party has just announced that
Minister of Agriculture Yusuke Satomi
has been named as Acting Prime Minister.
He will head the provisional
emergency government
that has been quickly set up
and has stated that
his first order of
business will be to name
a new cabinet to fill
the political void.
So then, the Agriculture Minister
is now the Prime Minister
because of his seniority?
That's who they chose?
But why him?
Well, I heard the job was foisted on him
by the party secretary.
Can you blame them?
Who wants responsibility
at a time like this?
What should we do about
the disturbing movement
near Tsushima Island?
Well, I suppose we'll just
have to wait and see.
Can the Foreign Ministry act?
We're still getting up and
running right now, sir,
but soon.
Well, at any rate, try to avoid
any unforeseen surprises.
Right. I'll let the ambassador know.
Noodles got soggy.
I knew this job wasn't going
to be easy, but come on.
Yeah, that guy.
He's a hard man to read.
Whoever the PM is,
it's our job to keep
the government afloat.
We need emergency powers.
I know.
We're 30 kilometers from
where Gojira's sleeping.
Scary, huh?
I'm more concerned about something else
right at the moment.
The decisions that will
be made to stop Gojira by the acting PM.
You want his job?
Not right now.
But maybe in ten years.
Yeah, if Japan's still around then,
you should run for office.
I'll help you, in exchange
for a nice cabinet position.
Akasaka was in Yokota
last night, so he survived.
Every politician needs two things,
strategy and luck.
He has both and now he's
Chief Cabinet Secretary.
You could be more
ambitious like him, y'know?
The Disaster Bureau is
still a unique path for you.
Just think about it.
You're practically in charge
of this group here.
No, I'm not. I'm here
to take the fall if needed.
Akasaka is a shrewd delegator.
If anyone gets a career boost from this,
that person's going to be you.
What exactly's wrong with that?
If you don't like politicians,
why'd you become one?
Because it's just friend or foe.
It's simple. I like that.
Excuse me, sir.
Bureau members have arrived.
I'm so happy to see you all.
Over half of our team
has returned to duty.
Thank you.
Our hearts are broken
over all those we've lost.
Let's do this for them!
Honor their sacrifice.
We're all hurting.
But I assure you that together
we can and will prevail!
For our country's sake.
I ask you, please pour
your hearts and souls
into completing our work!
I beg you!
Well, let's get to it!
Yes, sir!
- Chief Mori.
- Yes?
Where are we with the freezing plan?
At the moment, we've got
several private companies
formulating 24 different
blood pro-coagulants,
using silica, thrombin, and other agents
you'll see here in these specs.
We're hoping at least
one of them will work.
What about samples?
We've asked GSDF for some living samples
and they're retrieving
them now as we speak.
Roger that.
Samples retrieved. Orders?
I'm requesting that some be
sent directly to BSL4 labs.
Very good. Send the remainder
to any P3 level lab,
and it doesn't matter if it's
a public or private one.
But, sir, these samples are
government-classified substances.
I know, but we need
diverse info on Gojira.
No change to radiation levels.
They're still reading
at Below 1 Sievert.
Still sleeping.
And apparently
storing radiation in its belly.
Shift change. Let's go.
Yes? Yaguchi.
It's me. I'm arriving in five minutes.
Secure a meeting with
the acting Prime Minister.
So then, you wish
to provide us with something
to assist in our fight, is that correct?
Yes. There is a movement centered on
China and Russia,
to take Godzilla from under
the control of the Japanese government,
and put it under the control of
international organizations.
Many countries are aligned
with that opinion, too.
However, as for the US government,
we strongly hope that Japan and the US
can perfectly control Godzilla together.
Okay.
From the government's point of view,
it is for that reason
that we would agree
to a two-plus-two cooperation.
However...
As army experts will
remain as the backbone
of the government,
we have to respectfully
decline your offer
to remain at the center
of the decision-making.
In place of that, we will...
So a US-Japan Gojira research coalition?
The way I see it,
the more knowledge, the better.
Now let's clear some space.
Nice to meet you.
I'm Rando Yaguchi.
This is from GSDF's latest
unmanned surveillance system.
It froze shortly after the attack.
Same as the D2 simulation.
Just as I thought.
It appears that Godzilla
has something like
a built-in phased-array radar.
If so, then that means
it can instinctively
detect and intercept
any approaching objects.
Squad 2, this is CV1.
Five minutes from point zero.
Ten minutes remain. Over.
Copy that. CV1. Over.
After cross-referencing
the field data with Tsukuba's,
I believe we've discovered how
Gojira plans to propagate,
I'm sure of it.
With abilities like these,
it could rapidly colonize
the entire world.
Its body can evolve.
Make itself smaller.
Or even... sprout wings
capable of flight.
Let's go.
And that will mark
the end of the human race.
Before that happens, using our
nuclear wisdom is the only road
to salvation for mankind.
Are you serious?
I'm not really supposed
to be sharing this info,
but, the Defense Secretary wants to use
a warhead against Godzilla.
What'd the White House say?
Yes, because there's now a 13% chance
of Godzilla landing on the west coast.
The UN's ready to move, too,
and the Security Council
has set up a multinational strike force.
The US is serious.
Afraid so.
They say that to end
the threat of Godzilla,
a nuclear missile is the only
weapon that could kill it.
The missile they're
going to use is the B83
which is 75 times stronger than the bomb
that was dropped on Hiroshima!
They're dropping that on Tokyo?
Well, I was ordered to evacuate.
I see. So it's highly likely. Isn't it?
Yes.
But I don't want to be here for it.
I won't see a third bomb...
dropped on the homeland
of my grandmother.
She lived through the last two.
We have no choice. Not with
the way things are now.
Tell them yes.
Certainly. We will
act accordingly that way,
President Ross.
Well, you heard it.
It isn't the first time
something crazy's been foisted on us.
That's for certain.
But this goes too far!
I agree.
Get the Chief Cabinet Secretary.
Sir.
A resolution has just been passed
by the United Nations Security Council
granting a US-led force
to exterminate Gojira.
As party to that, and participant,
we must obey it, and its tenets.
To do that,
the PM needs to be
vested with full powers
so I can authorize a nuclear strike.
Isn't there some other way?
Think of the devastation
it will cause to Tokyo.
I never imagined
that I'd go down in history
for something such as this.
Yaguchi, from here on out,
Gojira comes under US-led,
UN jurisdiction.
Post-war Japan is a tributary state.
"Post-war" extends forever, huh?
This is a bad choice.
No matter how enormous Gojira is
I doubt it can withstand the
million-degree heat of a nuke.
As a method of extermination,
it's our only viable option right now.
My team and I are on the verge
of a breakthrough,
with our freezing method.
There are still too many unknowns
with that plan of yours.
Besides, multiple nations
have pledged their support
to assist us with
a complete rebuilding effort,
provided we sign on, of course.
Despite our best efforts, we can't destroy
Gojira on our own.
So if this nation is to survive,
we have no choice but to put our fate
in the UN's hands.
You have to understand.
I have to look ahead, and think about
what's best for a post-Gojira Japan.
Damage is limited to just three wards.
But if we allow this strike...
If it happens,
that number will multiply.
The city's economy is
currently in a free fall.
Bonds and stocks are plummeting,
and if we can't put a stop to this soon,
the nation will go into default
on all of its loans.
For that reason, Japan needs
international funding
in order to survive.
So scrap and rebuild, huh?
To save Japan.
There isn't any other way.
Yaguchi. This is the reality.
All else is just a dream.
What? They're going to
use a thermonuclear missile?
And drop that thing here?
The government just gave the UN
its sanction to do so.
That's insane.
There's still so much we don't know.
Gojira might even be immortal.
We're faced with two choices,
incinerate it with a nuke,
or freeze it with a drug.
Yeah, I guess we do
have two choices here,
but both are bad.
Man is more frightening
to me than Gojira.
If we're to do something,
we have to do it quickly.
The UN will be giving
time for evacuation.
That's our window for
finishing the freezing plan.
Okay. We got good
results on a coagulant,
but formulating it is one thing.
Producing it's another.
To freeze all of Gojira's blood,
we've estimated we'll need
672 kiloliters of coagulant.
I'm trying to secure
facilities for that now.
What if we can't?
We have to do it!
Don't give up.
Our country is depending on us all.
Every chemical company you know.
Contact them now, and ask them
to open every line possible!
You will? Thank you!
I'm sending all
pertinent data to you right now.
And please let everyone
know that we need production
finished by tomorrow at the latest.
Cross-checking's
complete by all the groups
we've reached out to.
Well, well.
I guess spreading knowledge works.
We're still working
on logistics for police
and MLIT to ship the coagulant.
I can handle that,
but I need METI to coordinate
with the pump makers.
Hey, I was just told that
if we agree to buy them,
Shanghai will get
three tanker trucks to us.
Any size.
Yes, that's correct.
We still need five more wheel loaders.
We have news, sir.
Ambassador Lansing relayed
coalition projections.
According to current readings,
Gojira's energy beam will be restored
to previous levels in 360 hours.
That means the creature
is likely to resume
activity again in 15 days.
I see.
A charter home will be
leaving in an hour.
All remaining staff, prepare
to leave immediately.
The start time for the nuclear strike
against Godzilla has been decided.
Countdown will begin in five minutes.
So, it's too late to turn back now.
Japan has been given
a two week grace period
in order to evacuate
remaining residents.
That may seem long
for the Allied Forces,
but it's too short for Japan.
What they ask...
that we somehow evacuate
millions of people from their homes...
is far easier said than done.
I agree.
But 3.6 million people?
That's insane!
We don't have the manpower
for a job that size!
What about the millions more
in neighboring prefectures?
What are we doing about them?
The governor protests
the sacrifice of Tokyo!
Look, this is a national decision,
not a municipal one, got it?
But, sir. Relocating that many people
in two weeks is impossible,
we can't do it.
For the sake of
all those people's lives,
you have to.
The moment Gojira stirs,
the strike is going to be moved up,
and we don't want people here
when that happens.
Regardless of collateral damage,
a thermonuclear missile
will be launched from
a sub at that time.
As per the coalition's decision.
Ridiculous! It's easy for them to say
with us in far-off Asia!
They told me they'd do the same
if Gojira would have
surfaced in New York.
Please proceed in an orderly fashion,
and if you're travelling with children,
please hold their hands.
Land prices are soaring in West Japan.
Food is short.
Kanto area shops and
businesses have all been
shuttered and the city's
full of the unemployed.
The yen's plunged, of course.
Investors are scared.
Except those profiting from it.
People come in all forms.
Good and bad.
So did you uncover anything?
'Course I did.
That is my job, after all.
I'll use it in an article I'm
hoping can be published,
on the day prior to the bomb drop.
Some new Gojira material.
In exchange, we can control
the announcement timing.
How's that sound?
It sounds very good.
So Goro Maki hated
the radiation sickness
that took his wife's life with
every fiber of his being.
He hoped to find a way to render
radioactive materials harmless.
Well, if something like that
could be possible,
then so, too, could the creation
of new material.
He must've feared
the military would use it.
That certainly would
explain why he redacted
the DOE data.
Professor Maki hated
radioactive materials.
And possibly even anyone or
anything who worked with them.
And that includes Japan,
which left his wife to die.
But then he leaves his data
with a note that says
"Do as you please"?
What a strange guy.
But just what did Maki do in the end?
Thank you for this meal.
Agh. Hmm.
You solve the chart yet?
No, not even with
the help of a brilliant
cryptographer who came
highly recommended.
You hear anything from the US?
I don't think we can
rely on them too much.
Not right now.
We've taken a
multi-tiered approach to try
and decipher Maki's info,
but it's bizarre.
This chemical schematic
is quite confusing.
Resembles a mandala.
I've even tried working
backwards from the solution
and still can't figure it out.
This Maki. Was the man insane?
Even I'm baffled by these lines.
Why'd he put it on paper
instead of an electronic file?
Perhaps... it's meant to be folded?
You know. With a lot of us eating now,
it makes me wonder about Gojira there.
Do you think that it gets hungry?
No doubt.
Yeah, but look, the thing's got
some really crooked teeth.
It can't even prey
on nuclear waste. Hmph.
Origami.
Huuuh...
It's not eaten.
We finally
figured out the entire pattern.
This new information
came from making folds,
just like in origami.
What we've done is focus on
radiation as its energy.
When the schematic's folded,
it's a molecular chart
for converting elements in the body.
Gojira's body has molecules
that can do this.
And the proof of this is in the unknown
radioactive isotope.
I'm sure of it!
The way it works is when either
hydrogen or nitrogen enters the body,
it's converted into
the necessary molecules.
Gojira's a mixotroph
with an organ that converts
decaying heat into
the energy that sustains it.
That's my hypothesis.
Questions?
It can live anywhere where there's
water or oxygen, huh?
So basically everywhere.
What you're saying
is that Gojira is not only
a threat to mankind,
but also an organism
that could potentially
be indestructible.
Is that right?
If the latter's true,
we have no certainty the coagulant
will be effective once it's
inside Gojira's body,
killing the Yaguchi Plan.
Yeah, possibly. So what now?
We raise the certainty of it working
through a series of tests.
Exactly, and the first thing
that we'll do
is analyze this structure.
Top to bottom.
I've already got supercomputers running
parallel analysis, but results are still
several weeks away I've been told.
But we only have ten days left, Yasuda.
I know. That's why I've asked MEXT
to use their global connections.
A call from Japan.
They're requesting parallel computing
on info about the Gojira creature.
Tell them we're sympathetic,
but there's no way we can
do that since ours is
a closed system, and a
proprietary one, at that.
We just can't risk
our data being stolen.
Oh, come, don't be like that.
Have some trust in your
fellow man for once. Right?
Please tell them that our answer is yes.
We'd be happy to help them.
Hey, we've done it!
We've solved Maki's riddle!
Here, look!
See!
Incredible.
You see there. It's not
the cell membrane itself,
but an extremophile configuration
that inhibits cell membrane activity.
You understand?
This inhibitor could mean
the blood coagulant plan
is still a viable option, and
one that might actually work.
It looks good.
Okay.
I get the feeling Maki anticipated this.
Maybe he saw the arrival
of Gojira as a test.
One for mankind, the world,
and of course, Japan.
Does his "Do as you please"
include nuclear weapons?
Maybe so.
"Do as you please," right?
You know,
that's a pretty hard thing
to do in this country.
Yeah.
If you're alone.
Sir. I'm happy to
announce that we've managed
to iron out the last kinks
in the Yaguchi Plan.
We ask your approval to deploy it.
I'm sorry, Izumi,
but the UN resolution
has already passed.
Some say the US seeks a quick resolution
for one primary reason.
And that's to bury their
knowledge of Gojira.
Of course, and we already know that!
And you know the condition
that our country is in.
All due respect, why let other nations
blow our country up
when we could save it?
What you're saying is
the fate of our country,
it would be best
guided by our own hands.
Perhaps it's time that
Japan did as it pleased.
Yes, you're right.
So, my stamp.
Where do I affix it?
"Once the coagulate
has been administered"
as strategized, the blood will freeze
"and render the creature
immobile as a result."
Wordy, I know.
You have a name for this plan?
"Yashiori" after the legendary
saké that felled a hydra.
Very well. We'll run
this op in five phases.
Akasaka worked out the details.
Requested vehicles
have all been prepped.
Plus explosives drills
have been conducted
and quite successfully, I might add.
Forces are execution-ready.
I owe you thanks.
No, you don't.
It's our job.
Just two days left on the countdown.
Dammit. I still need
three days in order to
make the amount of coagulant we need.
Is there any way the
countdown could be suspended?
Who on the Security Council could we get
to help us stall?
Any suggestions?
Not China or Russia because they're too
geopolitically close to us.
How about France?
Nuclear country.
I'm sure they'd be
interested in biology, too.
- Yeah.
- I've got a French contact.
Would you like for me to reach out?
Yes, please.
I'll try the Chief
of the European Bureau.
Do it. And I'm going to
call the Foreign Minister.
We need 24 more hours, people!
Sir!
France has petitioned
to interrupt the countdown.
China and Russia are opposed,
but we're maintaining silence.
That's because it isn't just hardliners
at the nucleus of
Washington and the Pentagon.
Japan has grown up enough to have
international trade deals on the sly.
Danger is another opportunity
for personal growth.
Our friends are progressing with
an effective deep freeze plan.
I think this country is betting on it.
And you're raising that bet also I see.
Nuclear weapons are a deterrent.
I've been trying to advise
Charles against it,
but it goes against the flow
of the mainstream.
And you and I must bear
the risk of retaliation.
Me, I'm okay.
But you, with your fastidious career
and the Patterson name, mud will stick.
And your dream of becoming president
in your forties will disappear.
Hey, Kayoco.
Good luck.
Yeah.
A joint strategy, huh?
Our countries can raise
the chance of success
by partnering up.
The US'll give my plan a shot?
Gotta admit I'm surprised.
Well, it helps to have me as a friend.
Whatever you need, I can get,
whether it's vehicles or technology.
Even drones if you need them.
So, what do you say?
I'm in, but there is
no guarantee of them
coming back in one piece.
Of course. I'll bill
the Japanese government later.
We were able to finish
the number of inhibitors
that you needed. That's right.
You can send over
the tankers to pick them up.
They're done.
We have material and coagulant.
Everything will be
operation-ready in a few hours.
You can give HQ the green light.
Yaguchi. Are you sure
you won't reconsider
accompanying the front line troops?
I have to be there
because a political decision
might be needed.
And if so, I have to make it.
It's still risky.
Directing from the rear's safer.
Don't you want to be
the PM in ten years?
If we're not able to pull this off,
there may not be a country left by then.
If I don't make it,
there are lots of others
who can take my place.
Such as you.
You'd make a great leader.
You've kept me going
through this. Thank you.
Don't thank me.
Thank Akasaka's mentoring.
Good luck.
Thanks. Now go save this country.
Operation Yashiori will be dangerous!
The risk of radiation exposure
could result in both sickness and death!
I cannot promise that
all of you will make it back!
But know that your work will matter!
The greatest strength
that this country has
is you, its people!
The SDF. It's the last fortress
that can protect this nation,
and you are its soldiers!
The future of Japan
is now in your hands.
Protect it.
Roll out!
Yes, sir!
Weather readings were
just confirmed, sir.
Optimal conditions as hoped.
Skies are clear.
Northwest wind is at two meters.
It's holding steady and...
If conditions remain steady,
the plume should blow out to the bay
and minimize the impact to the city.
All platoons are
on the ground standing by.
The US attack drone
squadron is in the air
in its designated holding pattern.
Happy to report.
All systems are go, Chief.
Just waiting on one thing.
Word from Tokyo that
the evacuation is complete.
We've only got one shot
at this so we can't wait.
Let the local governments
know we're proceeding
and to enact curfew.
Roger that.
Alert Kanto area municipalities.
Have them issue a mandatory
curfew for all citizens!
Indoor confinement, fifty-hour minimum!
Roger! And Commander,
we've just gotten word that
the train car detachment...
it's approaching the zero point!
Then let Operation Yashiori commence!
Phase 1 Diversion! Begin!
Success! The train blasts
were effective, sir!
Proceed to Phase Two!
Commence with the aerial assault!
Contacting US Forces, sir!
Command, this is Bravo 1.
Target in sight, engaging.
Copy that.
First wave airborne. Engaging.
Sir! The target is discharging
photons from its dorsal fins!
Gojira's taking down the drones
just as we anticipated.
First sortie destroyed!
Don't stop.
We're going to wear that thing down
and keep it discharging
energy. Until it's spent!
Second drone sortie destroyed.
Third drone sortie commencing attack!
Target moving to
predetermined coordinates.
Third sortie destroyed!
Contamination zone is growing.
Radiation. It's exceeding
the permitted amount.
If we stop now, all will be lost.
So continue the attack!
Fourth sortie destroyed!
Launch fifth sortie now!
Those beams. They've stopped discharging
from the fins.
But something strange is happening.
How the hell can it do that?
Fifth sortie has been destroyed.
That thing's plume.
It's doubled in intensity!
Hang on. Can't stop yet.
Launch the sixth sortie now!
Volume is decreasing, Commander.
The target's flame has just ceased!
Luring target to Kill Point 1 complete!
Right! Begin Phase Three!
Stationary blasting!
Ignite!
Radiation is at expected levels.
Now fixing target at Kill Point 1!
Right. Start Phase Four. Guided blast!
Target is down!
Kill Point 1 fixing complete!
Launch final phase!
Deploy special crane platoon!
Roger! First platoon! Forward!
Crane Platoon One.
Hydra-Slayer One.
Move out! Cranes 12 to 14,
deploy to battle positions
behind BP2 per your orders!
Hydra-Slayer One, Crane 11,
and BP1 in deployment zone, over.
Crane 11, Hydra-Slayer One, copy!
Standby with engines ready!
Deploy outriggers!
Approach BP1 and when ordered,
commence injection!
Crane 12 and BP2 deployed.
Hydra-Slayer One. Crane 15.
All vehicles deployed.
Engaging hook-up. Over.
Crane 15.
Hydra-Slayer One. Copy!
Stay at outer operation range!
Begin the injection!
Injecting coagulant!
All pumps initiate!
RC is operational!
Okay, raise the output pressure!
Target the mouth as much as possible!
Commander, 20% of supply administered.
The dosage target is now exceeding 30%.
Crane Platoon One.
They're gone.
Dosage is working!
Look, the target's slowing down!
Now's our chance!
Deploy all train bombs!
Do it now!
Gojira. He's fallen!
Then roll out
the second and third platoons!
Second and third platoons. Forward!
Freeze the bastard!
Do it! Administer all at once!
Fifty percent of supply administered!
The first 20 tanks are almost empty.
Got it. Switch tanks to 21
and above! Quickly!
Sixty percent of supply administered!
Seventy-five percent of supply gone.
We've now passed the coagulant
minimum that was projected.
Ninety percent of supply administered!
One hundred percent used!
Critical point's been reached!
The target's skin
appears to be stiffening!
Please let this work.
Did it work?
Oh, no! The target has resumed activity!
Full evacuation now!
Change positions! Hurry!
All troops, abandon attack
and evacuate to the holding area!
Chest area temperature
has dropped to negative 196 degrees.
Gojira. It's completely shut down!
Operation Yashiori...
Appears to be a success.
Thank you. All of you.
We were down to just under an hour,
which was far too close for comfort.
But we wouldn't have even had that
if the PM hadn't been able
to convince France.
'Scuse me!
Come and look at this survey data.
Huh.
Gojira's new isotope
has a half-life of 20 days.
And then halved again a month from now.
It'll be gone in two to three years.
Right. That's good news
for the residents of Tokyo.
Yeah.
Thank goodness.
Good work.
Yaguchi, I've been told
that the Satomi cabinet
will soon be resigning en masse.
All in line with your scenario, correct?
Wasn't mine.
This was all Satomi's scenario.
The capital and the government
are in shambles right now.
It's a good opportunity
to rebuild it right.
And speaking of which, once the relief
and reconstruction bills
have been passed,
the event that will happen
afterwards is the next election.
To resuscitate Japan
and its 3.6 million refugees,
we'll need a new leader
and a new cabinet.
This country was devastated before
but it rose from the ashes.
It'll do so again.
The countdown was only suspended.
But it'll restart if Godzilla
begins moving again.
Nuclear weapons will
be used if that happens.
I'm really amazed you agreed to that.
Well, I had to keep the world satisfied.
Now Japan, no...
all mankind, must coexist with Gojira.
So you shared the data with France.
Yes, with France, and the entire world.
But still I regret nothing.
I like this "by-any-means"
approach of yours.
Therefore... don't quit.
When I'm President of the US,
you'd be ideal as
my Japanese counterpart.
Your Japanese puppet, you mean.
The fact remains
that casualties were high.
And accountability comes with this job.
A politician must decide
whether to own it or not.
I myself choose to own it.
Well, like Maki said,
"Do as you please."
Hmph.
I guess now's not the time to quit.
Because things aren't settled.
Not yet at least.
Please rate this subtitle at www.osdb.link/5t874
Help other users to choose the best subtitles